<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Bandlow&#39;s Page</title>
    <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jason Bandlow&#39;s Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jbandlow.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-17 Oslo</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-17-oslo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 09:14:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-17-oslo/</guid>
      <description>Today was the final day of this great trip. We treated it as a bonus day, since with the Fram Museum yesterday, we had done everything we hoped. After the luxurious breakfast at our hotel (Scandinavian hotels really seem to do this well!) we headed out to the Historical Museum. This had a lot of interesting historical artifacts, including Viking-age collections, as well as a lot of items from areas and time periods that had little to do with Scandinavia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-16 Oslo - Fram Museum</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-16-oslo-fram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:49:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-16-oslo-fram/</guid>
      <description>As our trip comes to a close, today we completed the pilgrimage that the two of us have discussed for a very long time &amp;ndash; a visit to the Fram Museum of Polar Exploration in Oslo. It exceeded our already high expectations. The exhibits were detailed and very well-curated. The central, but by no means only, experience was walking around, on, and through the great ship Fram. They also have an excellent shop, with many books and items commissioned specifically for the Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-15 Bergen-Oslo</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-15-bergen-oslo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 23:30:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-15-bergen-oslo/</guid>
      <description>After two great weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve left our floating home on the Viking Sky, and are back to being independent travelers. It was an early morning, we had to be out of our cabin by 8:00am, and off the ship by 9:30. As I was drinking my morning coffee looking out at the port, I saw a submarine leaving the docks, with two guide ships alongside.
We spent the morning lazily wandering around Bergen and seeing a few more of the sights, including St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-14 Bergen</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-14-bergen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 20:56:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-14-bergen/</guid>
      <description>Today we docked in our final stop on the cruise, Bergen, the third largest city in Norway with a population of about 300,000. It feels somewhat strange to be in a city again after so much time in much more rural areas. Bergen has a rich history and Jessica and I spent the day just walking around taking in the sights and visiting a couple of the museums.
The first museum was the maritime museum, which had a history of Norwegian shipbuilding from Viking era ships to modern cruise ships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-13 Eidsdal</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-13-eidsdal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 21:22:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-13-eidsdal/</guid>
      <description>Today we were in Eidsdal, and it was definitely the most beautiful day of the trip so far. The weather was sunny an nearing 80 degrees. Eidsdal is a very small farming town, without a port big enough to accommodate our ship. So to visit, we anchored at sea, and there were periodic tender boats (basically our lifeboats) shuttling folks to shore.
The main activity for the day was a self-organized hike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 07 12 at Sea</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-12-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 21:53:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-12-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>Not much to say today, we were at sea all day and Jessica and I mostly spent it resting. Last night we crossed back below the Arctic circle and we have been rewarded with fantastic weather. Blue skies and temperatures in the 70s. For the first time on the trip, the roof over the pool deck was retracted.
I had said I would talk through the upper decks of the ship, so let me start at the aft of deck 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-11 Lofoten</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-11-lofoten/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 07:12:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-11-lofoten/</guid>
      <description>If you ask a Northern European where the most beautiful place to see the fjords are, the standard answer will be Lofoten. This is a chain of islands extending off the western coast of Norway, just above the Arctic circle. They are connected by roads and tunnels to each other and the mainland, with the main road spanning a bit more than 100 miles, with an estimated driving time of three hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-10 Narvik</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-10-narvik/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 20:28:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-10-narvik/</guid>
      <description>Narvik is a small mining community on the shores of a fjord known as Ofotfjorden. If I understood our guide correctly, several hundred thousand tons of ore are exported by ship every day. It was heavily attacked by the Germans in World War 2, who were attempting to gain control of the mines, and there are many memorials and a large war museum in town. As with everywhere in the north country, tourism is growing in importance, and there is currently work being done on the ski mountain just above town to make it suitable for the World Alpine Ski Championships that Narvik will host in 2029.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-09 Tromsö</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-09-tromso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 12:03:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-09-tromso/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s adventure was in and around the city of Tromsö (pronounced Troom-suh). Considered &amp;ldquo;the capital of the north&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s a thriving city of about 80,000 people roughly equally divided into three main job categories: fishing, government services (including the university), and tourism. It is the northernmost city in the world with more than 50,000 people, and so has &amp;ldquo;the furthest north McDonald&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;the furthest north shopping mall&amp;rdquo;, etc.
Still north of the arctic circle, Tromsö, like everywhere we&amp;rsquo;ve been, sits in the Gulf Stream and so the climate is much more moderate than places of similar latitude like Prudhoe Bay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-08 Honningsvag</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-08-honningsvag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:36:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-08-honningsvag/</guid>
      <description>Honningsvåg is a small fishing village on an island just off the northern tip of Norway. By a political quirk, it is classified as a city (unlike Longyearbyen), making it the northernmost city in Europe. The island is connected to the mainland by a tunnel, making it possible to drive from here to anywhere in mainland Europe. It&amp;rsquo;s at 71°, as far north as northernmost Alaska, but the climate is much warmer due to the gulf stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-07 At Sea</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-07-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 21:17:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-07-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>Another sea day today. I spent some time nature watching over the side of the ship. The most common sight is the Northern fulmar. These look like gulls, their name even means &amp;ldquo;foul gull&amp;rdquo; due to their defense mechanism of spitting terrible smelling stomach juices at perceived threats. But in fact, they are members of the petrel family. They are highly efficient fliers &amp;ndash; our guide on the boat tour claimed that in the right conditions they can use less energy gliding over the water than standing still on land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-06 Longyearbyen</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-06-longyearbyen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 08:15:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-06-longyearbyen/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s scheduled excursion was a catamaran fjord safari. We followed this up with a visit to the Svalbard museum, and a final walk around town before returning to the ship for our 5pm on board time. We also had an 8pm reservation at &amp;ldquo;The Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table&amp;rdquo;, billed as the nicest restaurant on board.
The catamaran had nearly 90 of us onboard, although with two decks there was plenty of seating. It was chilly on the outer decks, especially with the wind, but easy to warm up when back inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-05 Longyearbyen</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-05-longyearbyen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 21:24:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-05-longyearbyen/</guid>
      <description>Today we sailed into the town of Longyearbyen on the island of Spitsbergen in the archipelago of Svalbard. Svalbard is halfway between the northern tip of Norway and the north pole, and is the furthest north location with permanent human settlements. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly large, with an area roughly the size of West Virginia. It was historically a port for whalers, and from the late nineteenth through the early 21st century was an important mining community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-04 at Sea</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-04-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:58:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-04-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>The 4th of July was very much a &amp;ldquo;ship day&amp;rdquo;. No land or other ships would have been visible all day, even if visibility had been perfect, which it very much was not. The captain gives a daily announcement at noon with general conditions.
From today&amp;rsquo;s announcement:
We are at 74&#39;39&amp;quot; North, 0&#39;28&amp;quot; West, in the Greenland Sea Current temperature is 46 degrees F We still have some whales following us The sea is calm There is an overcast sky with patchy fog Indeed, on that last point, we heard the foghorn blow intermittently throughout the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-03 Jan Mayen</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-03-jan-mayen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 06:52:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-03-jan-mayen/</guid>
      <description>This was our first day with no stop on land. To keep up with time zones, we set our clocks forward one hour overnight. We will do the same again tomorrow, so our two days at see are really only 23 hour days.
Mostly a sunny day, with temperatures around 50. Reports of whales near the boat, though I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen any yet. I saw spray and a splash of color once when I was running on the treadmill, but it could easily have been a porpoise, which are also in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-02 Isafjordur</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-02-isafjordur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 02:56:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-02-isafjordur/</guid>
      <description>Woke up early, and after waking up I spent an hour on the treadmill. It was extremely disorienting to be looking out the window as the ship was slewing into port while running. But if I looked at a fixed point it was fine.
Isafjordur is the largest town in the west fjords, with a population of about 3000. It&amp;rsquo;s about a 6 hour drive from Reykjavik, 30 minutes by plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-01 Departure</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-01-departure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:51:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-01-departure/</guid>
      <description>After another fantastic breakfast, I returned the rental car without issue and walked back to the hotel. We packed our luggage, left it at the desk and walked to the Iceland Museum, where we spent a few hours looking at artifacts from the time of settlement to about 1700.
After walking back to the hotel, we took a taxi to the ships terminal, where we were apparently the last people to be boarding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-06-30 Reykjadalur and Djupagilsfoss</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-30-reykjadalur-and-djupagilsfoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:09:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-30-reykjadalur-and-djupagilsfoss/</guid>
      <description>After we were both up, we enjoyed an amazing breakfast at the hotel. This was an open buffet of bread, sliced meats, smoked salmon, salad, yoghurts, etc., with an included carafe of coffee. Given Icelandic prices, we could easily have had the equivalent of a $100 meal.
After some discussion, we decided our plan for the day was the Reykjadalur Hot Springs Hike. After getting sorted, we left around 11:30 for Hveragerdi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025-06-29 Arrival in Reykjavik</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-29-arrival-in-reykjavik/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 22:40:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-29-arrival-in-reykjavik/</guid>
      <description>Awoke on Saturday the 28th to a message that our flight was delayed, from 11:10am to 2:30pm, and was presented with the option to switch flights. Since this made for a very tight connection in NY, I switched, though the best I could switch to was a 2:00pm. While in the airport lounge waiting for that flight, I saw that it was also delayed (until at least 3:00pm), and so I immediately switched back to the original flight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
