<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Bandlow&#39;s Page</title>
    <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jason Bandlow&#39;s Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:58:37 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jbandlow.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-04 at Sea</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-04-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:58:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-04-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 4th of July was very much a &amp;ldquo;ship day&amp;rdquo;. No land or other ships would have&#xA;been visible all day, even if visibility had been perfect, which it very much&#xA;was not. The captain gives a daily announcement at noon with general conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From today&amp;rsquo;s announcement:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We are at 74&#39;39&amp;quot; North, 0&#39;28&amp;quot; West, in the Greenland Sea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Current temperature is 46 degrees F&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We still have some whales following us&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The sea is calm&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is an overcast sky with patchy fog&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, on that last point, we heard the foghorn blow intermittently&#xA;throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-03 Jan Mayen</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-03-jan-mayen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 06:52:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-03-jan-mayen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was our first day with no stop on land. To keep up with time zones, we set&#xA;our clocks forward one hour overnight. We will do the same again tomorrow, so&#xA;our two days at see are really only 23 hour days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mostly a sunny day, with temperatures around 50. Reports of whales near the&#xA;boat, though I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen any yet. I saw spray and a splash of color&#xA;once when I was running on the treadmill, but it could easily have been a&#xA;porpoise, which are also in the area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-02 Isafjordur</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-02-isafjordur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 02:56:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-02-isafjordur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woke up early, and after waking up I spent an hour on the treadmill. It was&#xA;extremely disorienting to be looking out the window as the ship was slewing&#xA;into port while running. But if I looked at a fixed point it was fine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%8Dsafj%C3%B6r%C3%B0ur&#34;&gt;Isafjordur&lt;/a&gt; is the&#xA;largest town in the west fjords, with a population of about 3000. It&amp;rsquo;s about a&#xA;6 hour drive from Reykjavik, 30 minutes by plane. Fishing and tourism are the&#xA;biggest industries, but all of the government services (hospitals, court, etc.)&#xA;for the west fjords are located there, so the government is another major&#xA;employer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-01 Departure</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-01-departure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:51:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-07-01-departure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After another fantastic breakfast, I returned the rental car without issue and&#xA;walked back to the hotel. We packed our luggage, left it at the desk and walked&#xA;to the Iceland Museum, where we spent a few hours looking at artifacts from the&#xA;time of settlement to about 1700.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After walking back to the hotel, we took a taxi to the ships terminal, where we&#xA;were apparently the last people to be boarding. We went through the otherwise&#xA;empty check in process in a few short minutes and were quickly exploring the&#xA;ship. Our cabin is at the very aft of the ship on the port side, 6th deck (the&#xA;highest floor that is only cabins).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-06-30 Reykjadalur and Djupagilsfoss</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-30-reykjadalur-and-djupagilsfoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:09:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-30-reykjadalur-and-djupagilsfoss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After we were both up, we enjoyed an amazing breakfast at the hotel. This was&#xA;an open buffet of bread, sliced meats, smoked salmon, salad, yoghurts, etc.,&#xA;with an included carafe of coffee. Given Icelandic prices, we could easily have&#xA;had the equivalent of a $100 meal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After some discussion, we decided our plan for the day was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://siggadottir.com/reykjadalur-hot-springs/&#34;&gt;Reykjadalur Hot&#xA;Springs Hike&lt;/a&gt;. After getting&#xA;sorted, we left around 11:30 for&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Hverager%C3%B0i,+Iceland/&#34;&gt;Hveragerdi&lt;/a&gt;. It&#xA;was an easy 45 minute drive on the ring road, and we parked at the cafe at the&#xA;trailhead. The countryside was classic Iceland. On the ride home, Jessica mused&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I wonder if Icelandic has a specific word for &amp;lsquo;moss-covered rockscape&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Home?,&amp;rdquo; I jokingly speculated. &amp;ldquo;You can work out which meaning from the&#xA;context.&amp;rdquo; Silly, but it&amp;rsquo;s striking to realize how these alien landscapes are&#xA;simply normal reality for people here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-06-29 Arrival in Reykjavik</title>
      <link>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-29-arrival-in-reykjavik/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 22:40:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jbandlow.github.io/2025-06-29-arrival-in-reykjavik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Awoke on Saturday the 28th to a message that our flight was delayed, from&#xA;11:10am to 2:30pm, and was presented with the option to switch flights. Since&#xA;this made for a very tight connection in NY, I switched, though the best I&#xA;could switch to was a 2:00pm. While in the airport lounge waiting for that&#xA;flight, I saw that it was also delayed (until at least 3:00pm), and so I&#xA;immediately switched back to the original flight. Through this process, we lost&#xA;our Comfort+ seats on the original and ended up across the aisle from one&#xA;another in the very back of the plane. We were further delayed on the runway&#xA;before takeoff, and again on landing, making it look like the connection was&#xA;going to be a &amp;ldquo;run and hope&amp;rdquo; kind of thing. But it turned out that flight was&#xA;also delayed by an hour and so we reasonably easily left NY at ~1:00am. These&#xA;were main cabin seats more towards the front of the plane, and were somewhat&#xA;more comfortable, but still not great for a red-eye. In any case, we got some&#xA;patchy sleep and arrived without issue. Entering Iceland was easy, though there&#xA;was quite a long line to pick up the rental car.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
